<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>music on Willkommen !</title><link>https://nokx5.github.io/nokx5/de/tags/music/</link><description>Willkommen ! (music)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nokx5.github.io/nokx5/de/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://nokx5.github.io/nokx5/de/music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nokx5.github.io/nokx5/de/music/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started as a young boy playing percussions, then focused on jazz drums ðŸ¥ and later on vibraphone ðŸŽ¹ as well. I was very lucky to work with a very talented drummer and percussionist at the &lt;a href="https://conservatoirepopulaire.ch/">popular music conservatory&lt;/a>. I will list here some methods we used during my progression with him.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="drums">Drums&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Stick Control for the Snare Drummer &lt;em>By George Lawrence Stone&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Advanced Snare Drum Studies &lt;em>By Mitchell Peters&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Syncopation &lt;em>By Ted Reed&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Drummer&amp;rsquo;s Complete Vocabulary &lt;em>as taught by&lt;/em> Alan Dawson &lt;em>By John Ramsay&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Beyond Bop Drumming &lt;em>By John Riley&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The New Breed &lt;em>By Gary Chester&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Even In The Odds &lt;em>By Ralph Humphrey&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 Solos for Drum Set &lt;em>By Eckhard Kopetzki&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="vibraphone">Vibraphone&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>15 intermediate Jazz Duets &lt;em>By John La Porta&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Jazz Vibraphone Book &lt;em>By Dick Sisto&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Music Of The Day &lt;em>By Bill Molenhof&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mirror from Another &lt;em>By David Friedman&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="band">Band&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The practice of live music and development of the hear couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible without other musician. I am particularly grateful to two teachers of the &lt;em>Atelier Junior&lt;/em> at &lt;a href="https://www.amr-geneve.ch/">AMR&lt;/a> for letting me practice two different instruments with other young motivated musician. During the covid crisis, I missed the jam sessions and the live instruments a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, I met Dehlia, my partner, in this jazz environment. I replaced someone on the drums for a live concert and she was playing the double bass. â¤ï¸&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jazz is broad and alive!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>